Guide to the Field Family Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Field family collection
1804-1992
1804-1962
MS 630
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The collection consists of clippings, printed and near-print materials, photographs and other papers concerning the Field family of Stockbridge, Massachusetts. Family members figuring prominently in this collection include Cyrus West Field (1819-1892) and David Dudley Field (1805-1894).
Field family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were removed from the Brewer Family Papers, MS99; and were the gift of Diane Druin Gravlee, 1992.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The materials in the collection relate to the Field family of Stockbridge, Massachusetts. There are several scattered items of correspondence (folders 13, 22, 32), a small amount of memorabilia such as cards and invitations, and thirty photographs of family members and the Field house (folders 6, 12, 14, 20, 26). However, the bulk of the the collection consists of newspaper clippings and other printed matter about family members, in particular Cyrus W. Field, David Dudley Field, Emilia Ann (Field) Brewer, Rachel Lyman Field, Stephen Dudley Field and Stephen J. Field. The papers are arranged by family members. These papers were originally part of the David Josiah Brewer Papers, Manuscript Group Number 99.
Biographical / Historical
David Dudley Field (1805-1894): lawyer, law reformer; argued in the Milligan case (1867) concerning the jurisdiction of military courts as specified in the constituion; also faced controversy during the Erie Railroad litigation of 1869; most famous for his codification of the laws of New York state; also published Draft Outline of an International Code (1872), which was translated into Italian and French. Cyrus West Field (1819-1892): merchant, capitalist, promotor of the first Atlantic telegraph cable in 1866.
Families; Stockbridge (Mass.); Field, Cyrus W. (Cyrus West), 1819-1892; Field, David Dudley, 1805-1894; Field, Rachel, 1894-1942; Field family
- Inventory
  - Address by D. J. Brewer on the occasion of the presentation of an oil portrait of Cyrus W. Field to the town of Irvington-on-Hudson, New York, 1909 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Field and His Cable," American Jr. Red Cross News, Frances Margaret Fox, 1939 January (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Invitations and personal cards: Cyrus W. Field, 1879, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: Cyrus W. Field, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cover of Success, 1898 January (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photos of Mr. and Mrs. Cyrus W. Field, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "A discourse delivered at the ordination of the Rev. David D. Field..." by John Elliott, 1804 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Poem by David Dudley Field on his brother Henry's 70 th birthday, 1892 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Rev. David Dudley Field, 1894, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: David Dudley Field (1805-1894), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Extracts from notices of David Dudley Field (1805-1894) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photos of David Dudley Field (1805-1894), one with Musgrave grandchildren, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Emilia Ann Field Brewer to Mrs. David D. Field, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photos: Emilia Ann Field (Mrs. Josiah Brewer), undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Advertisement: "All This and Heaven Too," by Rachel Field, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Rachel Lyman Field, 1938-1943, 1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: Stephen Dudley Field, [1913] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - In Memoriam: Stephen Dudley Field, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Articles and clippings: Justice Stephen J. Field, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photos: Stephen J. Field, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Field Family announcement, 1861, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Field Family correspondence, 1934, 1935, 1939, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: Field Family, 1892-1941 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: Fields in Stockbridge, Mass., 1932, 1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Album: Field Family photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Photographs: Field Family (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Manuscript genealogical chart of the Field and related families prepared by Clara Wells Herbert[in Brewer Collection], 1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Memoirs of a Notable Wedding," by Reginald Rowan Belnap, 1927 August 6 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "The Fields of 'Field Elders,'" by Andrew R. Mack, 1950 November (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - David Dudley Field, His Ancestors and Descendants, by Emilia R. Field, with annotations by the author [*Yca 802 F 4 g; in Yale Memorabilia] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Addenda to the Field book by Emilia R. Field, and news clippings on the Field family, 1930-1931, 1934-1950 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - ALS to David Dudley Field from Eleazer Thompson Fitch, 1843 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Descendants of David Dudley Field and His Wife, Submit Dickinson" (A 25 thanniversary edition of the the original "The Family Tree of David Dudley Field and Submit Dickinson," compiled by Diane Druin Gravlee, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 33)